Hello everyone and welcome back to another edition of Director's Cut.
I'm joined here with Katherine.
Hi everyone.
And we have a special guest today, Kyle.
Hello.
So Kyle is going to be joining us and he's going to help us review this movie Top Gun,
an icon of the 80s.
Absolutely.
Kyle probably has some special insights being a California boy, so closer to Hollywood than
any of us.
I am a California boy and I was born in the 80s.
So two and two make four.
So all right, so this movie Top Gun, as I said, is from the 80s.
It stars Tom Cruise.
It also stars Val Kilmer.
And Meg Ryan makes a brief appearance in that movie as well.
Lots of famous people who got their starts in the 80s actually.
Right.
So this movie is kind of a war movie, but it's mostly a drama.
Put some romance and some...
And it's for guys.
It's a guys movie.
It's a guys...
Yeah, it is for guys.
Planes, motorcycles.
Yeah.
It's also a girls movie.
It is a little bit like...
Romance.
...romantic.
Hot guys in uniform.
A love story.
So for those of you who haven't seen it, it's basically Top Gun is a school, right?
Like a fighter pilot school where they learn to perfect their skills or something like
that.
These guys are all in training.
So it's a part of this Navy program.
So it's not the Air Force, it's the Navy.
And there's a big rivalry between Maverick and Iceman.
Right.
And Maverick's wingman is Goose.
Yeah, that's right, Goose.
And well, we're not going to spoil the movie for you if you haven't seen it, but there's
some drama between Val Kilmer, Iceman, Maverick, and Goose.
And so all in all, this movie is from the 80s.
When did you watch this movie for the first time?
Probably the 80s.
Really?
It would have been the mid-90s for me.
I wasn't any five-year-old walking around going, oh, Top Gun.
I don't know, I was the daughter of a military man.
So anything military we saw.
That's right.
Your father is also Navy, right?
Air Force.
Air Force, Air Force.
All right.
So what did you guys think of the movie?
Go ahead, Kyle.
Oh, I think it's a classic.
It's an American classic film, you know?
Haven't seen it, and then there's a few scenes in particular that are, you know, now famous.
And the song, I can't quite remember the exact words of the song, but the theme song
is...
Oh, I think it's Kenny Loggins?
Is it Take My Breath Away?
Oh, Take My Breath Away, yeah, Berlin.
Oh, it totally is, I've forgotten about that.
He kind of had that, I don't know, 80s kind of cute, all-American charm thing that he
brought into, well, SNL skits for the next 20 years to come.
Right.
He was, I think he was the man of the 80s and the 90s, wasn't he?
He was.
That was all before, you know...
Brad Pitt?
And he went off the rocker.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, that is a whole other thing to talk about, how crazy Tom Cruise has become.
But maybe we can save it for...
We'll dedicate a whole segment to him in his loony attitudes recently.
But apart from that, what is the most memorable moment from the movie?
If I say it, I'll ruin it.
There is a very sad moment from the movie that for me sticks out.
My favorite moment is when he's driving the motorcycle and she's on the back and they're
driving into the sunset and he's wearing big Ray-Ban sunglasses.
And a leather jacket, right?
And a leather jacket.
Aviator jacket, yeah.
And Take My Breath Away is playing in the background and it's just perfect.
Now this is an interesting fact that actually Ray-Ban sunglasses was going through a very,
very hard time.
And by placing their sunglasses in the movie, they actually recovered a lot.
That's why aviator glasses became so popular.
It's mostly due to this movie.
Aviator glasses, the aviator jacket, leather jacket with like a little bit of fur on the
collar.
I had one of those.
He did?
With the bomber jackets, right?
Bomber jackets.
And also motorcycles, like those crotch rockets that you call them.
They started coming out in the 80s.
What's a crotch rocket?
A crotch rocket is a fast motorcycle.
It's a very fast street bike.
Oh, I didn't know that.
A lot of things about you are coming through here.
For anyone who doesn't know, Marco used to have a motorcycle and aviator glasses.
Aviator glasses.
And I was in the military.
I was in the military, so.
Come on, it's an icon.
I think like I'm putting all the pieces of life together and I'm seeing one thing.
Top gun.
That's what it was.
I actually did want to join the Air Force, but I couldn't because of my eyesight.
All right.
So.
Stuck on the ground.
We actually do have a clip from the movie.
One of the most memorable scenes as well is when they're in the bar.
And it's common, I think, in areas near bases, military bases.
I think you would know a little bit about that.
So when the military personnel is on leave, they usually go to a bar.
And sometimes, or most of the times, they're dressed in uniform because it looks cool,
I guess.
Yeah.
Do you like guys in your home?
I think it also has to do with like being able to pick people up.
Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
All right.
So.
Not to get all Freudian and whatever because I just said my dad was in the military, but
whatever.
No.
All right.
So let's listen to the clip.
You guys slide into Cougar's spot.
We didn't slide into Cougar's spot.
It was ours.
Okay.
Yeah.
Well, some pilots wait their whole career just to see them make up clothes.
Guess you guys are lucky and famous, huh?
No, you mean notorious.
I'll see you later.
You can count on it.
They were abused, children.
We're going to have a big time.
Always.
Okay.
I guess it's my turn, isn't it?
All right.
The bet is $20.
$20.
All right.
You have to have carnal knowledge of a lady this time.
On the premises.
Come on, man.
The bet's a bet.
I don't know.
It just, uh, just doesn't seem like it.
It just, uh, just doesn't seem fair.
For you, I mean.
But, uh, she's lost that loving feeling.
She's lost...
No, she hasn't.
Yes, she has.
She has not lost that loving feeling.
Because she's lost it, Matt.
Come on.
I hate it when she does that.
Excuse me, miss.
Hey, hey, hey.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of this.
You never close your eyes anymore when I kiss your lips.
There's no tenderness like before in your fingertips.
You're trying hard not to show it.
Maybe, but maybe...
That song.
It's like I've never seen that approach.
No.
How long have you two been doing this, Zach?
Oh, I don't know.
Since, uh...
puberty?
Right, puberty.
I'm Charlotte Blackwood.
I'm Maverick.
Maverick?
Is your mother not like you or something?
No, it's my call sign.
I'm a pilot.
That's right.
A naval aviator.
Actually, we've only done this, uh, twice.
I'll have to do it.
All right, we're back.
So, basically, I think this is a common situation, right?
Two military guys at a bar trying to pick up girls.
Jamming on the piano.
Now, do you think that guys in uniform look attractive?
Yeah?
Well, what is it?
They're clean.
But they, you know, they put themselves together, you know?
They shave.
They're tailored.
Yeah, the uniforms are tailored, right?
So, it fits well.
And they've got the shoulders.
So, they're thin or, well, they're in shape.
They're clean-shaven.
And, yeah, so I guess that's...
Short hair as well, right?
They can't have long hair.
Short hair.
So, everything is just a clean cut.
Yeah.
It's definitely a look.
What about girls in uniform?
I don't think...
I don't think that they've started making uniforms
that are actually flattering in any way.
You know, they're generally very flattering for men.
I think they're not supposed to be flattering.
Right.
Because, you know, you would have issues.
Were you saying that was the problem with the Ecuadorian navy?
It was, it was.
No more women.
It's actually a very common issue.
Like, it's co-ed and you're locked up for three months,
you know, you can't go out, can't see families,
and all of a sudden, you know,
it becomes a mess in there sometimes.
So, but, yeah, I don't think they're supposed to be...
Flattering.
Flattering uniforms.
All right.
So, all in all, how would you rate this movie?
Because it's a piece of my childhood,
and I love Val Kilmer.
Shh.
You do.
I love Val Kilmer.
Really? You're an Iceman lady, are you?
Yeah, I love Val Kilmer.
Well, there's a whole...
I don't know if you guys are familiar with Chuck Klosterman,
but he has a theory of advancement that I will go into it another time.
Wow.
But, Val Kilmer is like the stereotypical advanced actor.
He is...
The method actor is very weird.
And he does seem to be very, I don't know, sophisticated.
I don't know if sophisticated is the word I'd think of, but...
Maybe I'm just picturing him as Batman.
Batman.
Or like...
He was the best Batman, though.
It's a whole other conversation, too.
A whole other conversation.
No way.
Yeah, that's an argument right there.
But, okay, I'll give it an A.
Okay.
Yeah, solid.
Solid A.
What about you, Kyle?
I give it an A, absolutely.
It's a must-see.
Must-see.
All right.
All three of us agree, I give it an A as well.
I think it's a great movie.
It's actually a great movie to test out your sound system on.
If you ever buy a big screen TV and a home theater,
test it with that movie, yeah.
It's definitely worth it.
That's pretty much true of any Tom Cruise action film from the 80s or 90s.
Days of Thunder.
Mission Impossible.
Drop the hammer.
That's Days of...
I'm going to drop the hammer.
All right, so that's all the time we have for today.
We hope to see your questions and or comments on our website englishpod.com
and we'll see you guys next time.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.